「良医」前情回顾
Previously on "The Good Doctor"...
今天我负责急诊室
I'm covering the E.R. today.
医院肯定忙疯了
Gonna be a madhouse.
是啊
Yeah.
本急诊室和里面的所有人现在都已隔离
This emergency room and everyone in it is now under quarantine.
已经有三位病人感染了一系列呼吸病毒
A serious respiratory virus has infected three patients.
带我去医院
Take me to the hospital.
我们得去拍片
We are going to your appointment
确保你大脑里没有肿瘤
and making sure your think-melon remains tumor-free.
我的免疫系统没有了
I no longer have an immune system.
我的捐赠者出发了吗
My donor's on his way, right?
你怎么会接我们的捐献者的电话
Why are you answering our donor's phone?
因为他在隔离区
Because he's here in quarantine.
我老婆在里面  我得进去
My wife's in there. I need to get in there.
如果我出事
If something happens to me,
儿子需要有人照顾
our son needs someone to take care of him.
把你的口罩戴上
Put your mask back on.
为什么
Why?
因为我被感染了
Because I'm infected.
好消息是  我觉得我更喜欢摩根了
On the bright side, I think I'm growing on Morgan.
雷兹尼克医生
Dr. Reznick.
摩根
Morgan.
他不需要死
He doesn't need to die.
他签了不抢救预嘱
He signed a DNR.
他不该签的
He shouldn't have.
我们取到他的捐赠者骨髓
We're gonna get his donor's marrow.
你需要马上进行手术
You need surgery now.
没有手术室
There's no operating room.
我们得即兴发挥了
We will have to improvise.
用你的手指来堵住洞
Use your finger to plug the hole.
然后呢
Now what?
利姆医生
Dr. Lim?
复发了
It's back.
救救我儿子  救救我儿子
Help my son! Help my son!
公车站
13路  开往阿尔马登
27路  开往花山
13N路  开往阿尔马登
311路公车
311 bus.
两块三毛五
$2.35.
花山路
花山路左侧
Left on Blossom Hill...
凯兰
Kellan!
科特尔街
科特尔街右侧
Right on Cottle Street --
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy?
圣特蕾莎左侧
Left on Santa Teresa --
我觉得他有点不对劲
I think there's something wrong with him.
-待会给你口罩  -能给这位孕妇拿个口罩吗
- We'll get you a mask. - Can we get a pregnant woman a mask?
凯兰  你能听见吗  求你们了
Kellan, can you hear me? Please!
里面是空的
It's empty.
凯兰
Kellan!
子午线右侧
Right on Meridian --
雷兹尼克医生需要你
Dr. Reznick needs you.
他不回答
He's not answering.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy --
别喊  那样只会更糟
Don't yell. It'll only make it worse.
好吧  我该怎么办
Okay -- what should I do?
跟他说说手术
Tell him about the surgery.
把你知道的所有细节都告诉他
Give him every detail you can.
圣诞老人皮特肠系膜下动脉破裂
Santa Pete...has a torn IMA.
他的腹腔有出血
He's hemorrhaging into his belly.
血压是87/54并急速下降
His BP at 87 over 54 and dropping.
大隐静脉移植术
A saphenous vein graft.
我们可以做
We can repair the IMA
大隐静脉移植术修复肠系膜下动脉
with a graft from the saphenous vein.
-我们只需  -我不需要诊断
- We just -- - I don't need a diagnosis,
我需要另一位外科医生
I need an extra set of hands.
给我2-0缝合线  血管钳和11号手术刀
Get me a 2-0 silk, vascular clamps, and an 11 blade.
离手
Clear.
充电到两百焦
Charge to 200 joules.
离手
Clear!
我们刚救了他的性命  而且侵犯了他的权利
We just saved his life... and violated his rights.
我们可能失去行医执照
We could lose our licenses.
不会的  你只是遵循了
You won't. You were following instructions
-一位主治医生的指示  -不  我没有
- given by an attending. - No, I wasn't --
先稳定他的情况  我再去找安德鲁斯
Let's get him stabilized so I can go to Andrews
跟他说说关于取骨髓的事
and talk to him about getting him some marrow
这样我们才没白忙活
so this wasn't a waste of time.
闭上嘴
Keep your lips together
像吹蜡烛那样呼吸
and breathe like you're blowing out a candle.
我做不到  做不到
I c-- I can't -- I-I can't.
小凯  深呼吸  深呼吸
Kel -- deep breaths. Deep breaths.
你是医生对吧  病毒的事有进展了吗
You're a doctor, right? Any update on the virus --
-我感染了吗  -没有  没红疹  没发烧
- Do I have it? - No -- no rash, no fever.
这是你的哮喘发了
This is your asthma --
我们什么时候能回家
When can we go home --
你的肺部过度换气
Your lungs are hyper-inflated --
他们最好派更多医生进来
They better send in more doctors,
因为那个怪胎崩溃了
because that weirdo melted down --
大家都闭嘴
Everybody shut up!
给我闭嘴
Just shut the hell up.
这里有好多人情况危急
We have multiple people in serious condition,
包括一位资深医生和我的儿子
including a senior doctor and my son.
你们的这些问题都暂时等等
Your questions are gonna have to wait.
我需要一个喷雾器
I need a nebulizer.
在隔离区里  和感染的病人在一起
It's in isolation -- with the infected patients.
我从药房订一个
I'll order one in from pharmacy --
来不及了
No time.
良     医
第二季    第十一集
你要自制喷雾器吗
Making your own nebulizer?
差不多吧
Something like that.
你闯进来的
You broke in?
不是
No.
老爸  我看见那把电击枪了
Dad -- I saw the Taser.
我没用  只是拿来吓唬...
I didn't use it. Just threatened to...
你可太蠢了
That was dumb.
长长地深呼吸
Long, deep breaths.
你给她上最大量的氧气了
You got her on maximal oxygen?
是的  她的体征稍微恢复了一点
Yeah. Her vitals have recovered slightly.
疾控中心要给马来西亚爆发的病毒
The CDC is sending a PCR test
做一次聚合酶链反应检测
based off the virus in the Malaysian outbreak.
那他们的治疗方案是什么
So what's their treatment protocol?
抗病毒药  类固醇  吸入式一氧化碳
Antivirals, steroids, inhaled nitric oxide
以及抗肿瘤坏死因子受体抗体
and anti-TNF receptor antibodies.
那正是我们给那两名飞机乘客
That's what we did for the two plane patients.
以及泰勒用的
And Tyler.
我们给利姆医生治疗得更早  结果会不同的
We got to Dr. Lim sooner, that should make a difference.
莫菲医生怎么样了
How's Dr. Murphy?
他还行
He's fine.
我在监控录像里看到他崩溃了
I saw his breakdown on the security feed.
他好点了  现在在给圣诞老人皮特做缝合
Better. He's closing on Santa Pete.
你有搞定他的策略吗
Do you have a strategy for dealing with him?
-我和朴医生可以  -朴在里面
- Dr. Park and I can -- - Park's in there?
他什么时候进去的
When did that happen?
就在几分钟之前
Just a few minutes ago.
他跑进来救他的儿子
He came in to help his son.
真是妙
Perfect.
你还在这啊
You're still here?
他们怎么说
What did they say?
你真是个好姑娘
Very kind of you.
难怪你和肖恩关系这么不错
No wonder you and Shaun get along so well.
他们怎么说的
What did they say?
新的检查有什么新发现吗
Did the new tests show anything new?
处理CT影像需要时间
They need time to process the CT images,
之后才会送给布莱兹医生
send them off to Dr. Blaize.
所以你对自己癌症复发的判断可能是错的
So you might have been wrong about your cancer coming back?
不
No.
不会
No?
要是你不确定自己是不是对的
How can you know you're not wrong
你怎么知道自己就是对的呢
if you don't know you're not wrong?
这是套路
This is how they do it.
首先他们会告诉你有点异样
First they tell you there might be something,
然后让你来做新的检查确认以前的检查
and then they order new tests to test the previous tests --
最后还是告诉你  他们一直都是对的
only to inform you that it was what they suspected all along.
真是个报忧的好办法
Very effective way of breaking bad news.
好吧
Okay...
要是你的肿瘤真的复发了  那意味着什么
And if your tumor really is back, what does that mean?
意味着我那手术
It means that I had surgery
以及大脑放疗都白做了
and let them pump radiation into my brain for nothing.
意味着我的记忆衰退是因为我的大脑快死了
It means that my memory loss is because my brain is dying.
意味着我大概还有一年  或者十四个月可活
It means that I probably have a year, maybe 14 months.
你该懂了吧
Enough meaning for you?
我们要怎么跟肖恩说
What are we gonna tell Shaun?
什么都别说
Nothing.
圣文德医院开了个亲朋休息房
St. Bonaventure's opened up a room for family and friends.
你来吗
You want to come?
扩大了隔离区  把脊髓捐赠者
We expand the quarantine, we move our marrow donor
和患者都移进去
and our patient into --
如果捐赠者感染了病毒  它会随着脊髓
If the donor has the virus, his marrow will transmit it
转移到你免疫力低下的患者身上
to your immunocompromised patient.
这些患者撑不过几小时
He'll be dead in hours.
要是不接受移植他也活不下来
As he will be without the transplant.
我们使用聚乙烯薄膜  从急诊室
We create a sterile pathway from the E.R.
到手术室开辟一条无菌线路
into this procedure room using polyethylene sheeting --
我不准
No, you won't.
承担风险的是我的人
The only people taking any risks here are my people,
我的患者  捐赠者
the patient, and the donor --
如果你出一点差错  遭罪的就是全医院所有人
And this hospital and everyone in it if you screw anything up.
但我反对的更大理由是  这方案没用
But my larger objection is... it won't work.
那个手术室不在负压状态
That procedure room isn't negative pressure,
病毒很容易就会传播到主通风系统
which leaves the virus free to escape to the main vent system.
我会想出办法来的
I'll figure something else --
清洁工工作间
Janitors' closets.
那里是负压的
They're negative pressure
因为那里有清洁剂和消毒剂之类的
because of the cleansers, sterilizing agents.
那些东西的气味和毒素不宜
Don't want those odors and toxins
飘散到患者所在的区域
to disperse to patient areas.
这里
Here.
那个小房间容不下两个患者
That closet doesn't have room for two patients.
我们可以在那里取出脊髓  但移植不行
We can do the extraction there, but not the transplant.
我们可以用地下室的这个布草间
We could use this linen room, in the basement,
那里也是负压的
which is also negative pressure
并且和清洁工工作间
and connects to the janitors' closet
由这个衣物槽相通
through this laundry chute.
取出脊髓后
Once the bone marrow is extracted,
我们将它通过衣物槽送至布草房
it'd travel through the laundry chute into the linen room.
你可以在那里进行移植
Where you could do the transplant.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy?
把患者的情况告诉我
Update me on patient status.
圣诞老人皮特的体征稳定
Santa Pete's vitals are stable,
没有术后感染的迹象
no sign of post-op infection.
三区的托比正在接受静脉点滴
Toby is in Bay 3 receiving an IV drip;
埃斯特的ST
Ester's ST --
我觉得你逼他太紧了
I think you're overloading him.
不  思考医疗方面的事情
No. When he's dealing with medicine,
有助于他不受其它事物的干扰
he's not distracted by... everything else.
这有帮助  继续  肖恩
It helps. Keep going, Shaun.
埃斯特的ST段压低有所提高
Ester's ST depressions have improved.
这应该也有帮助
That should help, too.
埃斯特的ST段压低有所提高
Ester's ST depressions have improved,
维奥拉的羊水破了
and Viola's water broke.
什么  什么时候
What? When?
似乎就在刚刚
It appears quite recently.
急诊室
鉴于你受孕只有36周
Given you're only 36 weeks gestationally,
且没有感染的迹象
and there's no sign of infection,
婴儿应该可以在子宫内待至少24小时
the baby should be able to stay in utero for at least 24 hours.
如果在那之前隔离结束了...
If the quarantine is done before --
你不会再次崩溃的对吧
You're not gonna fall apart again, are you?
应该不会  维奥拉
I don't think so, Viola.
嘈杂声没了  喊叫声也少了很多
The buzzing is gone, and there is much less yelling.
除了你
Except you.
让你崩溃的是嘈杂声和喊叫声
It was the buzzing and the yelling,
而不是因为我们和三个
not the fact that we're trapped with three people
死于高传染性疾病的患者困在一起
who have died from a highly infectious disease?
这没什么值得担心的
That's not something to worry about.
我要么已经传染了  要么没有
I either have the virus or I don't,
并且根据以往的国家隔离死亡率来看
and, based on past national quarantine mortality rates,
我们在统计学上有很大可能幸存
we have a very good statistical chance of surviving.
但我一开始也不知道我会「崩溃」
But I didn't know that I would "fall apart" the first time,
所以我有可能说错了
so I may be wrong.
给你
Here you go.
你一直这样讲话吗
You always talk like that?
怎么样
Like what?
不论何时想到什么
Just say whatever you're thinking
都直接说出来
when you're thinking it?
是的  诚实很好
Yes. It's good to be honest.
真希望我爸也是这样
Wish my dad was like that.
朴医生非常诚实  他总是分享自己的见解
Dr. Park is very honest. He always shares his opinions.
有见解  也有情感
There's opinions. And then there's feelings.
你父亲从不告诉你他爱你吗
Your dad doesn't tell you that he loves you?
怎么了
What?
他只是...从不在身边
Well, he's just... not really there for us.
他刚刚为了帮你
He did just risk his life, and his career,
不顾自己的性命和事业闯进隔离区
to break into a quarantine to help you.
确实
That's true.
但多数孩子希望即使不是生死攸关
But most kids want their dad there
他们的父亲也能在身边
even when it's not life and death.
我很遗憾
Sorry for your loss.
情况如何
Status?
氧饱和度92
O2 SAT is 92,
呼吸频率下降为16
respiratory rate is down to 16.
肺听起来清晰了些
Your lungs sound clearer.
使用保守输液疗法
Keep pulmonary edema to a minimum
把肺水肿降到最低
with conservative fluid management.
使用呋噻米控制我的中心静脉压低于8
Use furosemide so my CVP's under 8.
当然
Absolutely.
我爱这个地方
I love this place.
我总是说到死之前都会做这个
I always said I'd be doing this 'til the day I died.
这下好了
Ta-da.
我们治疗得及时
We started your treatment early.
你很快就会回去给深夜醉汉治疗颅脑损伤了
You'll be back to repairing late-night, drunken head injuries in no time.
我忘了在我妈生日给她打电话
I forgot to call my mom on her birthday.
我有很多事都忘记做了
I forgot to do a lot of stuff...
泰勒很好
Tyler was sweet.
他是个好男人
He was a good guy.
最好把他放到我们看不见的地方
Best to put him out of sight.
看到他  对我们两个都不好
It's not a healthy reminder... for either of us.
泰勒的口罩上有裂缝
Tyler's mask had a tear in it.
病毒很可能是雾滴状
It's possible the virus is droplet-based,
而不是空气传播
not airborne.
血液或唾液也许经由航班乘客
Blood or saliva could've made its way through his mask
穿过了他的口罩
from the airline passengers.
不幸的是  直到我们确认之前
Unfortunately, until we know for sure,
还是要进行封闭
we're still on lockdown.
不过我会告知疾控中心
But I'll let the CDC know.
你有时间吗
Do you have a minute?
紧急吗
Is it urgent?
不太算
Not really.
小凯
Kel --
怎么了
What's up?
你为什么搬走了
Why'd you move away?
我是住院医生  需要跟着工作走
I'm a resident, you go where the job takes you.
凤凰城就不需要医生吗
They don't need doctors in Phoenix?
对我来说  那是个难得的好机会
This was an excellent opportunity for me.
而且不到两个小时就能飞到  我不...
And it's less than a two-hour flight; I'm not --
几个月来  你都有我的棒球时间表
You had my baseball schedule for months
但你只来过一次
and you came for one game
还一直在弄你的电脑
and you were on your computer the entire time.
我第二天有考试
I had exams the next day.
那你何必来呢
So why'd you bother coming?
很好
Good...
慢点
Slowly...
很好
Good...
虽然碎冰很美味
As delicious as these ice chips are,
我觉得我可以吃固体食物了
I think I'm ready for some solid food;
他们有送点饼干吗
did they send in any cookies?
莫菲医生说的很清楚  放屁之前都不能吃
Dr. Murphy was very clear -- no food until you fart.
想象这是从北极直接运过来的
Just imagine they're straight from the North Pole.
-鲍勃  你准备好了吗  -当然
- Bob, you ready? - Of course.
我要做骨髓提取
I'm doing a bone marrow extraction,
我还需要人来帮忙处理些血腥的东西...
and I need an extra set of hands to handle some bloody stuff...
把骨头和脂肪从干细胞中分离出来
separating bone and fat from stem cells.
谁还没被我说的话吓坏可以来帮我
Who here isn't freaked out by what I just said and can help?
埃斯特是个医生
Ester's a doctor.
你是医生吗  为什么刚才不...
You're a doctor? Why haven't you --
我是兽医  已经退休了
Veterinarian. Retired.
都是治病的  跟我们来
Blood is blood. Follow us.
胎心还是在每分钟130到140次之间
Fetal heart rate is still between 130 and 140 BPM.
宫缩间隔为十七分钟
Contractions 17 minutes apart.
发生什么了  是我的宝宝吗
What's happening? Is it my baby?
维奥拉的血压是180/100
Viola's BP is 180 over 100.
她可能有先兆子痫而且可能会癫痫发作
She may have preeclampsia and an oncoming seizure.
我们得催产
We need to induce labor.
不  他不能生在这儿
No. He's not being born in here.
我们得等到隔离结束
We are waiting for quarantine to end.
你的胎盘供血不足
Your placenta isn't getting enough blood flow.
我们得让他出来
We need to get him out.
这是你第一次生宝宝
This is going to be your first baby.
我第一次接生
And mine.
开始注射支气管扩张剂
Start bronchodilators.
利姆医生  能听见吗
Dr. Lim, can you hear me?
氧饱和度还在下降
O2 SATs are still dropping.
推注麻醉药
Push paralytics.
开始插管
Starting intubation.
喂  什么情况
Hello? What's going on?
什么情况
What's going on?
利姆的氧饱和度在下降  她的肺不充气
Lim's O2 SATs are crashing. Her lungs aren't inflating.
里面充满了液体和分泌物
They're filled with fluid and secretions.
-把电话拿起来  -我腾不出手
- Pick up the phone. - I've got my hands full.
维兰纽瓦  快拿起电话
Villanueva, pick up the phone.
好  给我看看情况
Okay, show me what's going on.
她的呼吸系统彻底衰竭了
She's in full respiratory failure.
她需要更多的肺支持
She needs more pulmonary support.
给她上双水平气道正压通气
Get her on BiPAP.
也许能争取点时间
That might buy us some time.
或者我们干脆先不管她的肺
Or we take her lungs out of the equation.
给她做体外膜肺氧合
We put her on ECMO,
在体外给血液供氧...
oxygenate her blood outside her body...
她的肺会有时间愈合
her lungs will have time to heal.
我们不能在急诊室做体外膜肺氧合
We can't do ECMO in the E.R.
我们也不应该在急诊室做
We aren't supposed to do abdominal surgery
腹部外科手术
in the E.R., either.
求你了  教我怎么做
Please, walk me through it.
在她的股静脉上方找块地方做好准备
Prep an area over her femoral vein.
这太吵了
That's very loud.
能看到头部吗  莫菲医生
Any crowning, Dr. Murphy?
不  她的宫口只扩张了六厘米
No, she's dilated at 6 centimeters,
我还摸不到胎儿的头
and I don't feel the head.
离她羊水破了已经七个小时了
It's been seven hours since her water broke.
宝宝卡住了  用奥波德氏操作法
The baby's stuck. Use Leopold's maneuvers
来确定胎儿的位置
to identify the location of the baby.
胎儿处于横位
The fetus is transverse.
他大概在朝左侧三十度的位置躺着
He's lying roughly thirty degrees to the left side.
这样宝宝生不出来
We can't deliver the baby.
什么  为什么不行
What?! Why not?
我们得把宝宝转过来
We need to turn the baby.
我们得进行外部抬头倒转术
We need to do an external cephalic version.
或者进行剖腹产
Or a C-section.
我协助过几次...
I have assisted on several...
那是在手术室有经验丰富的主治医生在场
In operating rooms with an experienced attending.
我们不能在这里进行剖腹产手术
We are not doing a C-section here.
把她的床倒下去  我去拿啫喱
Tilt her bed. I'll grab the gel.
好的
Okay.
所以如果...
So when...?
什么  如果什么
What? When what?
他被隔离的时候我不会告诉他
I get not telling him when he's in quarantine.
他已经够忙的了  但是...
He's got enough on his plate, but...
绝对不要
Never.
但是你第一次诊断出来的时候告诉他了
You told him when you were first diagnosed.
是的  那是个错误
Yes, and that was a mistake.
他逼着你去做检查  这救了你的命
He forced you take tests that saved your life.
不  最后结果是  并没有
Well, no, as it turns out, it didn't.
而且他太执着了  工作都分了心
And he became so obsessed and distracted
差点害死了一个病人
that he nearly killed a patient.
他是你的朋友
He's your friend.
我是他的导师  照顾我不是他的工作
I'm his mentor. It's not his job to take care of me.
一定要转动针管
Make sure you turn the needle
这样就可以从各个方向取到骨髓
so you're getting marrow from all sides.
慢点抽吸
Aspirate slower.
拉得越快越痛苦
If you pull fast, it's more painful.
坚持住  鲍勃
Hang in there, Bob.
我应该受点痛苦
I deserve a little pain.
你是他爸爸  你在挽救他的生命
You're his dad. You're saving his life.
我在儿子还不知道我是谁时就离开了
I took off before my son even knew who I was,
乘着破厢式货车浪迹天涯
traveled in crappy vans
住在破旧的旅馆里
to s-stay at crappy hotels
演奏着那些烂曲子
and play crappy music,
就为了赚钱买毒品
all so I could earn enough to get high.
你现在还是来了
You're here now.
我终于鼓起勇气面对他们时
By the time I got up the nerve to face them,
我前妻快死了
my ex was dying.
上帝也希望我能及时赶到救我儿子
God willing I did it in time to save my son.
梅伦德斯医生  克里斯的生命体征不行了
Dr. Melendez, Chris's vitals are bottoming out.
他的分泌物和肺音都越来越差
His secretions and lung sounds are worse.
我不知道还能等多久
I don't know how much longer we can wait.
给他用左旋去甲肾上腺素  准备移植
Administer Levophed, and prep him for transplant.
朴医生  克里斯出现了低血压
Dr. Park, Chris's in hypotensive crisis.
-快  -我在尽快
- Go faster! - Fast as I can.
莫菲医生  准备好了吗
You ready, Dr. Murphy?
是的  我摸到头了
Yes. I can feel the head.
我们得往一个方向转
We need to rotate in the same direction.
深呼吸  维奥拉
Deep breaths, Viola.
好的
Okay.
不  我做不到
Oh, I can't -- I can't do this!
用力抓住我的手臂
Squeeze my arm hard as you can.
胎儿转动了
The fetus is moving.
脑袋对着宫颈了
The head is facing the cervix.
再推一次
One more push.
-我们只需要  -停
- We just need - Stop!
胎盘早剥
Placental abruption.
她在大出血
She's hemorrhaging.
婴儿的心率在下降
Baby's heart rate is decelerating.
我需要两个大口径静脉注射管
I need 2 large-bore I.V. lines
和两单位浓缩红细胞
and start 2 units PRBC.
然后请给我找一个妇产科医生
Then please page an OB-GYN
来指导我首次单独做手术
to supervise my first solo surgery.
这太糟糕了
This is terrible.
不该是这样的
This is not how it's supposed to --
太好了
This is excellent.
加西亚医生会指导我做剖腹产
Dr. Garcia will be supervising me for the C-section.
她是这里的妇产科主任
She's the director of Obstetrics and Gynecology here.
我很确定
I'm sure she's much more qualified
她比你的妇产科医生更厉害
than your personal OB-GYN.
放松  你会没事的  情况如何
Relax. You're gonna be fine. What's the status?
神经麻醉已经打了
Nerve block is in,
我给她注射了一升生理盐水
and I gave her a liter bolus of saline.
加一点太葡糖酸盐
Throw some ChloraPrep down
切一个五厘米的下腹横切口
and make a five centimeter Pfannenstiel incision.
十号手术刀
Ten-blade.
克里斯已经准备好了
Chris's prepped.
正在插入中心静脉导管
Inserting central line now.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
血压90/50  血氧饱和度85
Pressure is 90 over 50, O2 SATs are 85,
心率110
heart rate is at 110.
只差你们那边了
Ready when you are.
还有一个就好了
One more and we're good to go.
我马上走
I'm on my way.
我正在刷手  你准备好往下扔后立马打给我
I'm scrubbing in. Call me the second you're ready for the drop.
腹部已经打开  拉钩
Abdomen is open. Retraction.
抽吸
Suction.
婴儿的心跳是110而且在下降
Baby's BPM is 110 and dropping.
发生了什么
What's happening?
莫菲医生  你看见子宫壁了吗
Dr. Murphy, do you see the uterine wall?
血压在下降
Blood pressure is dropping.
莫菲医生  子宫壁
Dr. Murphy, the uterine wall.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy?
你需要做一个浅切口
You need to make a gradual shallow incision
切开
and cut through it.
不要割伤了婴儿
You do not want to nick the baby.
-发生了什么  -每分钟心跳95
- What's happening? - BPM is 95.
莫菲医生  拜托了
Dr. Murphy, please!
莫菲医生  我们要打开她的供氧吗
Dr. Murphy, should we turn up her oxygen?
你得切这个切口
Dr. Murphy, you need to make the cut.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy. Dr. Murphy.
不
No!
安静  你们都安静
Quiet! Everyone quiet!
我得专心
I need to concentrate!
我能看到头
I can see the head.
我的孩子没事吗
Is my baby okay?
他没呼吸  得立刻做心肺复苏
He's not breathing. We need to start CPR now.
用小儿手按式急救气囊
Get a pediatric Ambu-bag
然后开始两指胸部按压
and start two-finger chest compressions.
维奥拉有点不对劲
There's something wrong with Viola.
她低血压而且心动过速
She's hypotensive and tachycardic.
她大出血了
She's bleeding out.
你得告诉他
You should tell him.
听听啊  你们相处得那么好
Look at that. Another reason why you two
又多了个原因
are so good together.
你们都对一件事很执着
Neither one of you are willing to drop a thing.
他应该知道
He deserves to know.
应该
Deserves?
你的世界就是这样的吗
Is that how things work in your world?
人人都能得到应该得到的东西
People get what they deserve?
肖恩应该被玩弄感情吗
Shaun deserves to be toyed with?
-谁玩弄他感情了  -你
- Who's toying with him? - You.
我是他的朋友
I'm his friend.
你突然拉他去公路旅行
You whisk him away on a road trip,
亲了他然后又离开小镇
kiss him and then leave town.
现在你又回到他的生活  和他一起住
Now you pop back into his life, move in with him.
肖恩不是什么你能玩来玩去
Shaun's not some hamster you get to play with
然后又毫不犹豫忘记要喂他的仓鼠
and then not think twice about it when you forget to feed him.
你会再次伤害他的  你知道的
You're gonna hurt him again. You know that.
我知道的
I know that.
我不计较你刚刚的话  因为你要死了
I'm gonna let that slide because you're dying.
玛丽娜·布莱兹医生
我出去接
I'm gonna take this outside.
气泡膜
Bubble wrap?
得确保它在运输途中
Need to make sure it doesn't break on the trip.
或落地时不会破
Or the landing.
梅伦德斯医生  我们准备好了
Dr. Melendez, we're ready.
通话中
收到  把骨髓放下来吧
Copy. Deposit the marrow now.
骨髓完好
The marrow is intact.
我们准备出发了
We're good to go.
我的胸
My chest...
特别疼
It really hurts.
他要心脏骤停了
He's going into cardiac arrest.
-我能做什么  -他的静脉膨胀了
- What can I do? - His I.V. is blown.
针尖断了
The tip broke off.
肯定进入心脏了
It must be in his heart.
加油啊
Come on.
莫菲医生  医疗的优先原则很是明确的
Dr. Murphy, the rules of medical priority are clear.
重点救治母亲
Focus on saving the mother.
莫菲医生  你该停下了
Dr. Murphy, you need to stop now.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy.
Dr. Murphy?
我们可以救他们两个
We can save them both.
请给我一升的生理盐水  一个塑料袋
Get me a liter of saline, a plastic bag,
一些医用胶布  还有克利克斯纱布
some surgical tape and Kerlix gauze, please.
谁会做心肺复苏术
Who knows CPR?
-在健康课  他们...  -跟我来
- Um, in Health, they ma-- - Come with me.
两指放在他胸部的中间
Okay, two fingers right here in the middle of his chest.
每秒按压两下
Press down twice per second,
每十五秒停下  然后挤压袋子
every fifteen seconds, stop and squeeze the bag.
-两下  -对  别太用力
- Twice... - Yes, don't press too hard,
不然你会压碎他的心脏
or you'll crush his heart.
好的
Okay.
你要做一个巴克里子宫填塞球囊为维奥拉止血吗
You're making a Bakri tamponade balloon for Viola's bleed?
-对  -那有什么用
- Yes. - What is that supposed to do?
它会在内部施压
It will control the bleeding by applying pressure
-从而止血  -孩子怎样了
- from the inside. - How's the baby?
我不知道这有没有用
I don't know if this is working.
-我只是  -别停
- I just... - Don't stop.
你准备好了吗  莫菲医生
Are you ready, Dr. Murphy?
将填塞球囊的底部缓慢地放入她的子宫颈
Feed the end of the pack slowly through her cervix.
当到达子宫的底部时  开始充气
Once you reach the fundus of the uterus, start inflation.
离手
Clear.
-那是第四次了  -我必须打开他的胸腔
- That's the fourth one. - I have to crack his chest.
-在这里吗  -从救生车里
- Here? - Get me rib spreaders
拿肋骨撑开器和十号手术刀给我
and a ten blade from the crash cart.
骨髓注入了
Marrow's in.
心率84  血压100/60
Heart rate's 84, BP's 100 over 60 --
各项体征都还不错
vitals look good.
我很抱歉之前的事
I'm sorry about before.
你会跟肖恩说你有好消息要分享吗
Are you gonna tell Shaun you got some good news?
是什么让你认为是好消息的
What makes you think it's good news?
因为你道歉了
Because you apologized.
我的癌症没有复发
The cancer's not back.
-那非常好  -不是非常好
- That's great. - It's not great.
只是好  不是非常好
It's okay. It's not great.
我因为脑脊液漏而得了脑膜炎
I have meningitis from a CSF leak in my head.
我基本上必须马上动手术
I have to have surgery pretty much immediately.
还有  不  我不会告诉肖恩
And, no, I am not telling Shaun.
你说对了一件事
You're right about one thing.
你不是他的朋友
You're not his friend.
因为朋友会告诉对方每件事
Because friends tell each other everything.
而且你是个差劲的导师
And you're a lousy mentor.
朋友会陪伴对方  而导师则教导对方
Friends are there for each other, and mentors teach.
不会隐瞒真相
They don't hide the truth.
我只是在为他着想
I'm just looking out for him.
他不像你  他不像其他人
He's not like you. He's not like everybody el--
不  他不像
No, he's not,
但他也不是什么无助的小孩
but he's also not some helpless child
需要一直被保护
who constantly needs protection.
他是个成人
He's an adult;
一个非常聪明  有同情心的成人
a very smart, caring adult.
而你现在真的需要像他那样的人来陪你
And you could really use someone like that right now.
这没有用  她还在流血
It's not working. She's still bleeding.
继续注射生理盐水
Keep injecting saline.
生命体征80/60  心率110
Vitals are 80 over 60. Heart rate's 110.
停止心肺复苏术
Stop CPR.
我要看他是否能自主呼吸
I need to see if he can breathe on his own.
都还好吗
Is everything okay?
不  他的肺部充满液体
No. His lungs are filled with fluid.
他在溺水
He's drowning.
去拿小儿喉镜  快
Get the pediatric laryngoscope stat.
安德鲁斯医生  她还是
Dr. Andrews, she's still --
不是安德鲁斯
It's not Andrews.
我可以看看她吗
Can I see her?
平均动脉压稳定在65
MAP is holding steady at 65,
但她刚短暂地进入严重的缺氧状态
but she was dipping into serious hypoxia for a short bit.
我可以看看她吗
Can I see her?
你把她照顾得很好
Good work, taking care of her.
谢谢你
Thank you.
孩子有胎粪吸入综合症
The baby has meconium aspiration.
抽吸导管
Suction catheter.
那很糟吗
Is that bad?
粪便物已经进入他的肺部
Fecal matter has settled in his lungs.
阻断他的呼吸道
It's blocking his airway.
我做错什么了吗
Did I do something wrong?
你很可能移除了部分
You most likely dislodged some of it.
不然他现在可能就窒息了
Without that, he would've suffocated by now.
正在清理他的呼吸道
Clearing his airway.
这是我人生中最重要的时刻
It's the most important moment of my life.
而我不在维奥拉的身旁
And I'm not there with Viola.
这就是以前的做法
This is the way it used to be done.
男人在外面等待
The men waiting outside.
现在更明白个中滋味了
Now we know better.
现在知道这很重要
Now we know it matters.
你认为你的祖父没那么爱你的父亲
Do you think your grandfather loved your father
-就因为  -住嘴
- any less just beca-- - Shut up.
忽视他  他只是爱发牢骚
Ignore him. He's just a grouch.
那是
Is that...?
我想你有新的起床闹钟了
I think you've got yourself a new alarm clock.
恭喜
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
我做爸爸了
I'm a dad.
他很好
He is okay.
圣诞奇迹
A Christmas miracle.
谢谢你
Thank you.
是利姆
It's Lim.
能给我些水吗
Could I get some water?
体外膜肺氧合
ECMO?
胆量过人
That was a ballsy move.
埃斯特·布卢姆  皮特·贝利
Ester Blum, Pete Bailey --
你们的聚合酶链反应和血清检测没有发现病毒
your PCR and serology came back negative for the virus.
你们已经没事了
You're officially cleared.
我们可以回家了
We're going home.
只有埃斯特能回家
Only Ester can go home.
你还需要一天的术后恢复
You're going to post-op recovery for another day.
我会陪着你
I'll keep you company.
我正好还想再见一个人
There's someone I want to see up there anyway.
涛声澎湃  浪花舞
On Dasher, on Dancer,
滔滔载我至远方
on Prancer and Vixen.
你的情况稳定了
You are stable,
没有骨髓排斥的迹象
no sign of marrow rejection.
接下来几周我们会严密监护你
We will be monitoring you over the next few weeks,
但你的病情肯定会好转的
but remission is a very real possibility.
我不知道该如何感谢你们
I don't know how to thank you enough.
我想我也该谢谢我爸爸
Guess I should thank my dad too.
他在这吗
Is he here?
术中出现了并发症
There was a complication during extraction.
鲍勃的心脏停跳了
Bob's heart stopped.
我们竭尽所能救他  但是
And we did everything we could to revive him, but
他死了
he died.
什么
What?
我们对你的遭遇深感遗憾
We're so sorry for your loss.
你是克里斯·桑托斯吗
Are you Chris Santos?
我叫埃斯特
My name is Ester.
我当时陪着你父亲
I was with your father when he...
他提到自己很后悔
He mentioned that he had lot of regrets.
但能够帮助你对他来说意义深重
But it meant a lot to him that he could help you.
听说给那位孕妇接生时你帮了很大的忙
Heard you were a big help during that delivery.
他们需要额外帮手
They needed extra hands.
你问我为什么轻易放弃你和你母亲
You asked me why I let you and your mom go,
为什么我不争取一把
why I didn't fight harder.
因为我不是什么好人
It's because I wasn't a good person.
我不是个称职的父亲
I wasn't a good father.
我父亲有句口头禅
My dad had this mantra --
男儿有泪不轻弹
Be like stone, never cry.
每当我情绪化  他就会重复这句话
If I got emotional or upset -- he'd repeat it:
男儿有泪不轻弹
be like stone,never cry.
这话让我更坚强
It made me stronger --
但这也不总是好事
which wasn't always a good thing.
我一生都躲在一堵墙后
Spent my life living behind a wall --
你母亲因此不得不也与那堵墙一起生活
which meant your mom got to live with that wall as well,
我们分开时  我感觉像个废物
and when we split up, I felt like a failure.
搬走能让我躲避现实
Moving away helped me hide from that.
我父亲的声音还在我脑中盘旋
My father's voice is still in my head.
但我在努力让它安静
But I'm working on getting it to be quiet.
我爱你  凯伦
I love you, Kellan.
永远
Always will.
凯伦
Kellan!
妈妈
Mom!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我没事  我
I'm fine. I, uh --
我帮助医生们给一位孕妇接生
I helped deliver a baby.
他很棒
He was amazing.
很高兴看见你  米娅
It's good to see you, Mia.
里面怎么样
How was it in there?
我治疗的那位病人没能挺过来
The guy I worked on didn't make it.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
我会永远记得这个圣诞
I don't think I'll forget this one.
我也是
Me neither.
我没法接受你不在我身边
The idea of you not being around wasn't okay with me.
我还能和谁喝波本
Who would I drink bourbon with?
我得有段时间不能喝波本了
I think my bourbon days are behind me for a little while.
我会等着
I'll wait.
肖恩
Shaun!
你肯定累坏了
You must be exhausted.
还很饿
And hungry.
所有三明治都有腌黄瓜
All the sandwiches they gave us had pickles in them.
这可不太好
Oh, that's no good.
不如去24小时早餐店
How about we go to that 24-hour breakfast place
吃点煎饼
and get some pancakes?
好极了
I would like that very much.
-你好格拉斯曼医生  -你好
- Hello, Dr. Glassman. - Hello.
-我今天接生了一个孩子  -听说了
- I delivered a baby. - Yes, we heard.
很抱歉我不能载你去拍片
I'm sorry I couldn't drive you to your appointment.
怎么样
How did it go?
我有脑膜炎
I have meningitis.
今天晚些时候我得做手术
I have to have surgery later today
治疗我的脑脊液渗漏
to fix the CSF leak in my head.
我认为该告诉你
I thought you should know.
挺好的
That's good.
脑膜炎总好过癌症
Meningitis is definitely not as bad as cancer.
这也能解释你的记忆流失
It also explains your memory loss.
你可以拿回你的驾照了
Now you can get your license back.
肖恩  你介意格拉斯曼抱你一下吗
Shaun, would you mind if Glassy gave you a hug?
我很愿意
I think that would be very nice.
为你骄傲
Very proud of you.
BGM: Have Yourself A Merry Little Christmas by Aimee Mann
♪ Have yourself a merry little Christmas ♪
♪ Let your heart be light ♪
♪ From now on, our troubles will be out of sight ♪